// Creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "It happens when the sender fails to communicate his/her message properly or when the intended message is not clearly understood by the receiver.",
    answer: "b. communication barrier",
    options: [
      "a. communication",
      "b. communication barrier",
      "c. process of communication",
      "d. strategies to avoid communication barriers"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "It refers to the natural or environmental conditions that hinder a successful communication transaction.",
    answer: "c. physical barrier",
    options: [
      "a. cultural barrier",
      "b. external noise",
      "c. physical barrier",
      "d. psychological barrier"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "These are issues like trauma, lack of confidence, fear, anger, frustration, and depression that may affect the communication process.",
    answer: "c. psychological barrier",
    options: [
      "a. external noise",
      "b. linguistic barrier",
      "c. psychological barrier",
      "d. semantic noise"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "It refers to the way a person responds in a communication situation affected by personal norms and traditions.",
    answer: "a. cultural barrier",
    options: [
      "a. cultural barrier",
      "b. linguistic barrier",
      "c. physical barrier",
      "d. psychological barrier"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "This is an example of a situation where linguistic barrier to communication becomes evident.",
    answer: "c. People do not understand each other’s language.",
    options: [
      "a. A professor explains his lessons eloquently in class.",
      "b. Elena is afraid to deliver her opening remarks.",
      "c. People do not understand each other’s language.",
      "d. The transmitter disrupted the speech of Ms. Reyes."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "This is one of the reasons why the claim may not be acceptable to some who stand for unity amidst diversity.",
    answer: "b. Different culture interpret words, gestures, and symbols differently.",
    options: [
      "a. Cultural diversity allows people to be unique and original.",
      "b. Different culture interpret words, gestures, and symbols differently.",
      "c. Traditions propagate through the preservation of norms and values.",
      "d. The values of people reflect."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "It is an example of semantic noise that hampers or impedes effective communication.",
    answer: "c. use of excessive technical jargon",
    options: [
      "a. horn of the taxi",
      "b. noise from the construction site",
      "c. use of excessive technical jargon",
      "d. chitchat of people"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which best defines NOISE in the context of communication?",
    answer: "d. It is anything that interferes with communication.",
    options: [
      "a. It is the sound of karaoke from your neighbor.",
      "b. It is any sound that occurs during the communication process.",
      "c. It is a sound that blocks or interferes communication situations.",
      "d. It is anything that interferes with communication."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is an example of a psychological barrier?",
    answer: "d. poor listening skills",
    options: [
      "a. ability to read minds",
      "b. dissatisfaction with customer service",
      "c. inattentiveness to detail",
      "d. poor listening skills"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which factors are considered cultural barriers to communication?",
    answer: "d. religion, world Meanings, and philosophy",
    options: [
      "a. economic status, age, and gender",
      "b. ethics, standards, and grammar",
      "c. politics, administration, and government",
      "d. religion, world Meanings, and philosophy"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Why does communication breakdown occur?",
    answer: "d. All of the above",
    options: [
      "a. It is because the information is overloading.",
      "b. It is because of a lack of attention among the audiences or receivers.",
      "c. It is because the listener or receiver has a very short attention span.",
      "d. All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which does NOT belong to the group?",
    answer: "d. verbal noise",
    options: [
      "a. external noise",
      "b. internal noise",
      "c. semantic noise",
      "d. verbal noise"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "“Mrs. Erlinda was invited as a speaker during the National Women’s Month. She talked about Gender Equality. She delivered her speech for almost 1 hour with more than 50 slides. The audience appeared uneasy and seemed uninterested after 20 minutes.” What barrier of communication is evident in this situation?",
    answer: "c. physiological barrier",
    options: [
      "a. cultural barrier",
      "b. linguistic barrier",
      "c. physiological barrier",
      "d. psychological barrier"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which communication situation displays physiological barrier?",
    answer: "d. The research teacher was discussing with his students about the problem when a song was played loudly from the other classroom.",
    options: [
      "a. The General Parents and Teachers Association (GPTA) president felt nervous when he started to speak in front of all the parents and guardians.",
      "b. The Municipal Agriculture officer is discussing certain agricultural crops management procedure in a community that is not very familiar with the topic.",
      "c. The newly-designated general manager of the restaurant was a bit hesitant to talk with the guests.",
      "d. The research teacher was discussing with his students about the problem when a song was played loudly from the other classroom."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which situation BEST exemplifies communication breakdown?",
    answer: "b. incorrect labeling of handouts to be used in product distribution",
    options: [
      "a. adjusting your language depending on the people you are talking to",
      "b. incorrect labeling of handouts to be used in product distribution",
      "c. listening to your friend’s heartaches and unsuccessful love stories",
      "d. looking for the positive characteristics or strengths of a speaker"
    ]
  },
];
